var fullquiz = { "JS" : [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "What is first aid",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Emergency treatment given to ill or injured persons",
                "b": "Basic treatment anyone can do before leaving the casualty alone",
                "c": "A quick fix for minor injuries",
                "d": "Keeping someone calm until someone else takes over"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Emergency treatment given to ill or injured persons",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "What are the three Ps in relation to first aid",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Preserve life. Prevent worsening. Promote recovery",
                "b": "Preserve life. Protect from injury. Prolong recovery",
                "c": "Prevent life. Promote worsening. Preserve recovery",
                "d": "Protect life. Prevent worsening. Promote recovery"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Preserve life. Prevent worsening. Promote recovery",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "Why do we do first aid? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "To preserve life",
                "b": "To make ourselves feel better for helping",
                "c": "To fulfil our part of the job role",
                "d": "For a bonus and rewards"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "To preserve life",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "Who is responsible for delivering first aid",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Everyone on board",
                "b": "The Master",
                "c": "The medical officer",
                "d": "The doctor"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Everyone on board",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "What is the first thing to check for when approaching a casualty?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Danger",
                "b": "Bleeding",
                "c": "Breathing",
                "d": "Someone else who can help"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Danger",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 2
       },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "What is triage",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Prioritising order of treatment for multiple casualties",
                "b": "Delivering care",
                "c": "Finding out what happened",
                "d": "Getting three people to help you"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Prioritising order of treatment for multiple casualties",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 3
       },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "What does A.B.C.D.E. stand for when triaging casualties",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Airway. Breathing. Circulation. Disability. Exposure",
                "b": "Airway. Bleeding. Cardiac. Disability. Electricity",
                "c": "Alert. Breathing. Circulation. Disability. Electricity",
                "d": "Airway. Breathing. Circulation. Death. Exposure"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Airway. Breathing. Circulation. Disability. Exposure",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 3
       },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "What technique do we use for opening a casualty's airway",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Head tilt, chin lift",
                "b": "Head lift, chin tilt",
                "c": "Head lift, chin up",
                "d": "Head up, chin down"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Head tilt, chin lift",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 3
       },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "How do we check for breathing",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Look, listen, feel technique",
                "b": "Use a mirror",
                "c": "Put your hand over the casualty's mouth",
                "d": "Put your hand on the chest"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Look, listen, feel technique",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 3
       },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "How long do we check for breathing",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "10 seconds",
                "b": "5 seconds",
                "c": "30 seconds",
                "d": "60 seconds"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Look, listen, feel technique",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 3
       },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "What should you do if the casualty is not breathing",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Begin CPR",
                "b": "Leave them - you can't help them",
                "c": "Put them into the recovery position",
                "d": "Call for help"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Begin CPR",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 3
       },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "What position do we put an unconscious breathing casualty into",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Recovery position",
                "b": "Turn them on to their back",
                "c": "Turn them onto their stomach",
                "d": "Sit them up"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Recovery position",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 3
       },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "Why is it important to deal with circulation injuries quickly? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "To prevent shock",
                "b": "To prevent the blood making a mess",
                "c": "To reduce the risk of hypothermia",
                "d": "To prevent clotting"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "To prevent shock",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 3
       },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "Which of these is it important to tell the medical officer when they arrives? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "What you found on arrival at the scene",
                "b": "An exaggerated account of what you think happened",
                "c": "Who you think was responsible",
                "d": "A root cause analysis"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "What you found on arrival at the scene",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 520,
          "chapter": 4
       },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "On encountering a first aid emergency situation, what is the first thing you should do? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Raise the alarm",
                "b": "Run for help",
                "c": "Wait for someone else to deal with it",
                "d": "Move any casualties"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Raise the alarm",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 521,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "question": "What is the best way to approach a casualty if possible? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "From the feet",
                "b": "From behind",
                "c": "From the side",
                "d": "From the head"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "From the feet",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 521,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "question": "What does DRsAB stand for? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Danger, Response, Shout for help, Airway, Breathing",
                "b": "Don't, Run, stop, Alert, Bridge",
                "c": "Danger, React, Scream, Airway, Breathe",
                "d": "Danger, Run, Shout, Alert, Bleeding"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Danger, Response, Shout for help, Airway, Breathing",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 521,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "question": "How do we turn a casualty from their front onto their back? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Superman roll",
                "b": "Spiderman roll",
                "c": "Batman roll",
                "d": "Ironman roll"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Superman roll",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 521,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 19,
          "question": "Why do we put a casualty into the recovery position? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "To maintain their airway",
                "b": "To keep them comfortable",
                "c": "To make it easier to look after them",
                "d": "To prevent them moving and causing more injury"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "To maintain their airway",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 521,
          "chapter": 2
       },
        {
          "id": 20,
          "question": "When would we not put a casualty in the recovery position?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "If we suspect a spinal or neck injuries",
                "b": "If we couldn't move them",
                "c": "If they had a head injury",
                "d": "If we suspect a broken leg or arm"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "If we suspect a spinal or neck injuries",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 521,
          "chapter": 2
       },
        {
          "id": 21,
          "question": "How do we monitor the casualty's condition when they are in the recovery position? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Regular checks of breathing, pulse and level of response",
                "b": "Doing another secondary survey",
                "c": "Talking to them to see if they answer",
                "d": "Watching to see if they wake up"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Regular checks of breathing, pulse and level of response",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 521,
          "chapter": 2
       },
        {
          "id": 22,
          "question": "Who states the minimum requirements of medical equipment that must be carried on board?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Medical regulations of the flag State",
                "b": "The medical officer",
                "c": "SOLAS",
                "d": "The shipping company"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Medical regulations of the flag State",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 522,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 23,
          "question": "What are triangular bandages used for?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "To support and immobilise upper limb injuries",
                "b": "To support and immobilise lower limb injuries",
                "c": "To wrap over other bandages to keep them clean",
                "d": "To clean wounds"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "To support and immobilise upper limb injuries",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 522,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 24,
          "question": "Why are gloves included in a first aid kit?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "To use as PPE for the first aider",
                "b": "To put on to the casualty's hands to keep them clean",
                "c": "To put on the casualty's hands to keep dressings on the hands dry and clean",
                "d": "To use when cleaning up any mess or spillages after dealing with the casualty"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "To use as PPE for the first aider",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 522,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 25,
          "question": "How long can you keep an open bottle of eye wash solution?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "You can't - it is no longer sterile once opened and must be discarded",
                "b": "1 week",
                "c": "2-3 days",
                "d": "Up to 1 month"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "You can't - it is no longer sterile once opened and must be discarded",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 522,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 26,
          "question": "What type of stretcher is often carried as a minimum requirement on board?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Neil Robertson",
                "b": "Paraguard",
                "c": "Spinal board",
                "d": "Basket"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Neil Robertson",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 522,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 27,
          "question": "What causes a casualty to faint?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "A drop in blood pressure reducing oxygen to the brain",
                "b": "A sudden shock",
                "c": "An increase in blood volume",
                "d": "An increase in blood pressure"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "A drop in blood pressure reducing oxygen to the brain",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 523,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 28,
          "question": "How long does a faint generally last?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "30-60 seconds",
                "b": "Over 2 minutes",
                "c": "5 - 10  seconds",
                "d": "More than 5 minutes"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "30-60 seconds",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 523,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 29,
          "question": "At what body temperature would a casualty start to suffer mild hypothermia?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "35C",
                "b": "37C",
                "c": "32C",
                "d": "38C"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "35C",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 523,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 30,
          "question": "How quickly should we try to raise the temperature of a  hypothermic casualty?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "1-2C an hour",
                "b": "3-4C an hour",
                "c": "1-2C a minute",
                "d": "3-4C a minute"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "1-2C an hour",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 523,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 31,
          "question": "What type of shock is caused by a loss of blood volume?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Hypovolemic shock",
                "b": "Electric shock",
                "c": "Anaphylactic shock",
                "d": "Cardiac shock"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Hypovolemic shock",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 523,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 32,
          "question": "In what circumstances should we use CPR?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "If the casualty has suffered a cardiac arrest",
                "b": "If the casualty is breathing",
                "c": "If the casualty has had a stroke",
                "d": "If the casualty is bleeding heavily"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "If the casualty has suffered a cardiac arrest",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 524,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 33,
          "question": "What is the difference between a heart attack and a cardiac arrest? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "With a heart attack the casualty is still breathing; they are not with cardiac arrest",
                "b": "There is no difference; they are the same thing",
                "c": "In a cardiac arrest, the casualty will still be breathing. They will not be breathing after a heart attack. ",
                "d": "There is no point doing CPR for a cardiac arrest, but it might help with a heart attack"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "With a heart attack the casualty is still breathing; they are not with cardiac arrest",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 524,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 34,
          "question": "Which of the following statements best describes the symptoms of a heart attack? ",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Crushing central chest pain radiating down the left arm, nausea, vomiting, and breathlessness",
                "b": "Unconscious, not breathing",
                "c": "Crushing pain on the right of the chest, nausea, and breathlessness",
                "d": "Pain on the left side of the chest going up into the neck or throat, and nausea"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Crushing central chest pain radiating down the left arm, nausea, vomiting, and breathlessness",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 524,
          "chapter": 1
       },
        {
          "id": 35,
          "question": "What is the purpose of doing chest compressions?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "To mimic contractions of the heart to push blood and oxygen around the body",
                "b": "To keep the heart beating normally",
                "c": "To prevent blood and oxygen travelling around the body",
                "d": "To reduce the blood flow into the heart"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "To mimic contractions of the heart to push blood and oxygen around the body",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 524,
          "chapter": 2
       },
        {
          "id": 36,
          "question": "When a casualty suffers a cardiac arrest, we should check for normal breathing. What is very slow noisy breathing called?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "Agonal breathing",
                "b": "Atonal breathing",
                "c": "Agnostic breathing",
                "d": "Abreviated breathing"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "Agonal breathing",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 524,
          "chapter": 2
       },
        {
          "id": 37,
          "question": "When starting chest compressions, what position should the hands be in?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "On the centre of the chest, between the nipples",
                "b": "On the left of the chest, above the nipple",
                "c": "On the right of the chest, below the nipple",
                "d": "On the centre of the chest, below the sternum"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "On the centre of the chest, between the nipples",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 524,
          "chapter": 2
       },
        {
          "id": 38,
          "question": "How many chest compressions should be done in each cycle of CPR?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "30",
                "b": "15",
                "c": "45",
                "d": "60"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "30",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 524,
          "chapter": 2
       },
        {
          "id": 39,
          "question": "At what rate should we perform chest compressions?",
          "options": [
             {
                "a": "100-120 per minute",
                "b": "80-100 per minute",
                "c": "140-160 per minute",
                "d": "120-140 per minute"
             }
          ],
          "answer": "100-120 per minute",
          "score": 0,
          "status": "",
          "module": 524,
          "chapter": 2
       }
    ]
}